Austin Downey

Bachelors of Science
Full-Stack Software Developer

2082508543



austinidowney@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-downey/



https://github.com/austinjdowney

Summary

As a software developer with experience in a plethora of different coding languages, able to adapt different concepts on the fly, including my psychology background to provide an emphasis on the user experience (UX). Passionate about full-stack development and watching an application come to life from the beginning.

Experience

Full-Stack Software Development Student

CodeWorks 3/2021 - Present

Server/Togo Specialist

Olive Garden 5/2015 – 11/2017; 7/2019 – Present

Fitness Counselor-Lead

Axiom Fitness 8/2017 - 7/2019

- Promoted to Lead Fitness Counselor
 - 10/2018 7/2019

Case Manager/Community-based Rehabilitation Service (CBRS) worker

Kuna Counseling Center 9/2015- 10/2016

Skills and Abilities

- JavaScript (Vue3.js)
- MVC design
- Node.js
- SASS (CSS)
- Bootstrap
- MONGODB
- J QUERY

- SCRUM (Agile)
- RESTful Api's
- Auth0
- C##
- .Net
- mySQL
- Chart.js

Education

Certificate of Software Development

CodeWorks

3/2021 - Present (Grad: 6/2021)

- 13 week intensive fast-paced program
- focused on full-stack end-to-end applications

Bachelors of Science Psychology

Pacific University 2011 - 2015

- Emphasis on neuroscience with clinical disorders
- Minor in Sociology

Volunteering

ALTERNATIVE SPRING BREAK THRU PACIFIC UNIVERSITY

-Volunteering in San Francisco with various homeless populations and shelters (40 hours volunteering, March 2013)

PACIFIC UNIVERSITY AMBASSADOR

Fall 2012 - Spring 2014

-Instructed incoming freshmen thru their freshmen orientation about the best practices at Pacific an

<u>Applications</u>

ECOSISTENT

-Full-stack application within a group of 4 developers completed in just under 2 weeks.

- Incorporated Vue.is, Node.is, SASS, Bootstrap, 3 RESTful Api's, Auth0, J Query, Chart.is and SRUM
- Application is a carbon emissions tracker for your house (i.e., electric and water usage), bike/walk miles to help encourage other modes of carbon free emissions, and car(s) that incorporate varying gas types that will influence your emissions (i.e., unleaded, diesel, hybrid) in relation to miles driven.
- Able to track your own emissions relative to the national average.
- Able to see your daily score and your last 7 daily emissions on your own and other user's profiles.
- Able to see a daily update of carbon emission news and air quality, based on your current location, on the home page.

BUGLOGGER

-First full-stack individual application incorporating Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, Auth0, and J QUERY.

- Able to create "bugs"/data and then be pushed to that "bugs" details page to edit (only for the "bug" creator) that "bugs" information.
- All users can create notes related to that specific "bug."
- Included differing rules where one could not delete a "bug" fully, the status would just switch from open/close, but if you created a note on that "bug" you would be able to delete that note.
- Additionally, be able to filter the closed "bugs" off the page and keep only the open "bugs."

KANBAN

-First full-stack partner developed application incorporating Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, J Query, Auth0, and SCRUM.

- An application geared towards the private organization of TODO lists, interests, inventory of materials, and more.
- An individual is able to create a "board" where you are able to make an infinite number of lists related to that "board."
- Create cascading tasks based off those lists, and furthermore be able to leave comments or reminders to help complete your lists and tasks.

INSPIRE

-Application designed within the first 4 weeks of coding with RESTful Api's incorporating 4 different end points and a real time customized clock.

- Background images from UNSPLASH that on refresh would change to a different HD randomized image.
- Randomized inspirational quotes that would also change on refresh, which also had the author hidden unless the pointer was on hover.
- Weather temperature was included in Fahrenheit based off the city, state you were located in.
- Task Manager to add tasks and then be able to track how many tasks were completed, relative to total amount of tasks, but upon completion would also include a strike through.